

Mehmet Akif Tütüncü

Istanbul, Turkey

♠ https://akif.dev

makiftutuncu

in makiftutuncu

y makiftutuncu

I'm a senior software engineer focused mainly on backend. I have more than 9 years of professional experience in software development. I've conducted consulting, training and worked with companies around the world such as Shazam, Socrata, Beam/MAF, sahibinden, Numbrs, Scalac and Conduktor. I am proficient in Scala, Java, Kotlin using both object-oriented and functional programming. I have skills in CI/CD, testing, databases, cloud applications, microservices. I am a fan of open-source software.

WORK EXPERIENCE

iO (Dec 2022 - Present)

Senior Software Engineer

Just started at this position

https://iodigital.com

Scalac (Nov 2021 - Oct 2022)

Senior Software Engineer

I worked with Conduktor as a consultant. I migrated part of their legacy Java API to a new Scala service. It included an automated mechanism to check for correctness. I helped build user and organization management features handling multiple Conduktor products.

⇔ https://scalac.io

Numbrs (Nov 2020 - Oct 2021)

Software Engineer

I worked in Personal Finance Management team. I was responsible for developing new features to Numbrs app backend.

https://www.numbrs.com

Sahibinden (Aug 2019 - Nov 2020)

Senior Software Engineer

I worked in the search team. The domains I usually dealt with were search, promotions and categories. I also automated the process of updating location and geo data.

https://sahibinden.com

VNGRS (May 2017 - Aug 2019)

Software Engineer

I consulted in multiple projects. In MAF Properties team, I worked in the kick-off process for their latest product. In Beam team, I helped migrate and maintain a mobile payment system. In Socrata team, I helped design, develop and maintain multiple backend projects.

⇔ https://vngrs.com

Linovi (Oct 2013 - Oct 2016)

Software Engineer

I started as a part-time here. Then joined Shazam team. I had varying tasks from developing features, fixing bugs, writing automated tests to maintaining projects.

iDivino (Aug 2012 - Aug 2013)

Android Developer

I worked part-time on developing games for preschool children.

PROJECTS

Effect

Functional effect library in Scala

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/effect

Scala, Functional Effect, Error Handling

Bookstore

A project demonstrating automated testing on backend

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/bookstore

Scala, Finch, ScalaTest, Postman, Docker, Flyway, Doobie, PostgreSQL

Muezzin

Android application and server

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/Muezzin

Scala, Java, Play Framework, PostgreSQL, Anorm, Akka

k-retry

Naive retry implementation

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/k-retry

Kotlin, JUnit

LANGUAGES

Turkish

Native

English

Professional

SKILLS

Frameworks/Libraries/Tools

Akka, AWS, cats, circe, Docker, Elasticsearch, git, Gradle, http4s, JUnit, Kafka, Play Framework, Quill, SBT,

ScalaTest, Spring Framework, tapir, ZIO

Databases

Cassandra, DynamoDB, Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL,

PostgreSQL, Redis

Progamming Languages

Go, Java, Kotlin, Scala

Techniques

Agile, CI/CD, DDD, Kanban, Microservices, SCRUM, TDD

TALKS

Dealing with Errors on JVM with e

ScalaUA 2020

https://youtu.be/HAQZtTZae_Q

Kotlin for Backends

sahibinden.com D2D

https://github.com/makiftutuncu/kotlin-for-backends

Typeclass 101

VNGRS Lightning Talks

https://youtu.be/jPiM9uBHpWI

Testing Web Backends With Scala

Test Hive

https://youtu.be/QnK8pyGUOac

ARTICLES

Scala Blog

(Dec 2015)

Android Blog

(Jan 2012)

Wordpress

http://makiftutuncu.wordpress.com

Blogspot

Instructor

http://androidce.blogspot.com

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Kodluyoruz

(Dec 2020 - Jan 2021) Izmir Institute of Technology

(Jan 2013 - Apr 2013)

Instructor

I gave introduction to Scala and functional programming

lectures.

I gave Android lectures in student club at my university.

EDUCATION

Izmir Institute of Technology

(Aug 2009 - Jun 2014)

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering

Education in English, focused on software, started my career halfway through with internships and part-time positions

CERTIFICATIONS

Complete Guide to Elasticsearch

Udemy

(Jun 2020)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate (May 2018)

Amazon